<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_features">
		<text>Features</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_features_rank">
		<text>Rank</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_features_rank_text">
		<text>
			Rank is a score system based on what a stalker has accomplished in the Zone.\n
			\nActions which you perform throughout your playthrough are recorded and each grant a varying number of points depending on the action in question.\n
			\nAs you accumulate more and more points your rank will gradually change as you pass through every milestone, with each requiring an additional 1,000 points on top of the requirements of its predecessor.\n
			\nMost of these actions are logged in the statistics tab of the PDA, which also contains an in-game leaderboard that keeps track of the current top-100 highest ranking stalkers.\n
			\nThere are currently eight total ranks available:\n
			\n• Rookie (0)\n• Trainee (1,000) (+1,000)\n• Experienced (3,000) (+2,000)\n• Professional (6,000) (+3,000)\n• Veteran (1,0000) (+4,000)\n• Expert (15,000) (+5,000)\n• Master (21,000) (+6,000)\n• Legend (28,000) (+7,000)
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_features_reputation">
		<text>Reputation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_features_reputation_text">
		<text>
			Reputation is a representation of how a stalker interacts with others.\n
			\nReputation is similar to rank but differs in that it isn't quite so linear - being able to both increase and decrease - and that it is based on your interactions with other stalkers rather than the environment.\n
			\nThe easiest ways to increase reputation are by completing tasks, providing first-aid, and killing your faction's enemies, whilst inversely the easiest ways to lose it are by cancelling or failing tasks, and killing neutral or friendly stalkers.\n
			\nIt should be noted that reputation is not to be confused with goodwill, which handles all stalker and faction relations. Reputation is largely an immersion-focused feature for the benefit of the player.\n
			\nThere are currently nine total reputations available:\n
			\n• Terrible (-2,000) (-500)\n• Dreary (-1,500) (-500)\n• Awful (-1,000) (-500)\n• Bad (-500) (-500)\n• Neutral (0)\n• Good (500) (+500)\n• Great (1,000) (+500)\n• Brilliant (1,500) (+500)\n• Excellent (2,000) (+500)
		</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>