<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions">
		<text>Factions</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_bandit">
		<text>Bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_bandit_text">
		<text>
			Bandits are members of the criminal underworld who operate in the Zone.\n
			\nWhether to flee from their past crimes or to make money from selling artefacts and dealing firearms, their actions leave them despised by almost everybody foreign to their ranks.\n
			\nThe faction consists of the Zone's many numerous gangs, operating separately of one another, and guided first by opportunity before any form of organised leadership.\n
			\nAmbushing unsuspecting stalkers, blocking routes and "taxing" those who pass, and even entrapping stalkers into debt are just but a few of their many illicit activities in the Zone.\n
			\nHere, criminals and gangsters can do whatever they want with little fear of consequence.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_clear_sky">
		<text>Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_clear_sky_text">
		<text>
			Clear Sky are a scientific faction dedicated to learning about the Zone's inner workings.\n
			\nDespite recent history they are generally considered to be a peaceful faction, preferring to invest their time and resources into research, rather than in playing politics.\n
			\nThey view the Zone and its creation as both a gift and a curse - an incredible event with unappreciated potential - and a threat to humanity if not properly kept in balance.\n
			\nIt was this latter part of their ideology which led them to near destruction, in chasing a stalker who they believed would greatly upset this balance, they fielded one of the largest forces ever seen in the Zone.\n
			\nWith the ensuing battles against the Monolith in their path, and the emission that followed them, the faction was left leaderless and in a state of disrepair.\n
			\nToday however they are led by Cold, who has helped them to rebuild and recover - carrying on the research of their predecessors and keeping the peace in the far southern reaches of the Zone.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_duty">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_duty_text">
		<text>
			Duty is a paramilitary organisation formed by former soldiers.\n
			\nCharacterised by their strict discipline and military attributes, their ideology is built upon the protection of humanity from the dangers of the Zone.\n
			\nIn view of this, Duty deals with the Zone's internal problems - the destruction of mutants and bandits - which greatly facilitates the daily lives of ordinary stalkers.\n
			\nDespite taking this hardline approach they have been known to cooperate with Ecologists, handing over artefacts in return for knowledge which could assist them in their ideological crusade.\n
			\nBecause of their actions they find themselves at constant odds with Freedom, a faction similar in size and strength, but whose attitude toward the Zone is of coexistence and preservation.\n
			\nAfter a short-lived truce at Yanov Station bloodily collapsed, their bitter rivalry has yet again embroiled them both in another deadly conflict with no clear end in sight.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_ecologist">
		<text>Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_ecologist_text">
		<text>
			Ecologists are an institute of government-backed research organisations.\n
			\nThere is no ecosystem anywhere else quite like the one found in the Zone, so naturally there is also a great interest expressed in it by the government.\n
			\nIt is for this reason that the faction exists - to study the artefacts, anomalies, mutants and other unnatural objects that can be found only here.\n
			\nThus far they have established two research labs, one in Yantar and the other in Jupiter, from which they conduct most of their secretive experiments.\n
			\nWhen working out in the field they are often accompanied by an escort, usually hired mercenaries or stalkers, or are otherwise armed themselves.\n
			\nMany stalkers who hunt for artefacts and rare mutant parts sell them to the Ecologists, as they are usually willing to pay much more than anybody else for them.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_freedom_text">
		<text>
			Freedom
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_loner">
		<text>Loner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_loner_text">
		<text>
			Loner
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_mercenary">
		<text>Mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_mercenary_text">
		<text>
			Mercenary
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_military">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_military_text">
		<text>
			Military
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_monolith">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_factions_monolith_text">
		<text>
			Monolith
		</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>