<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="ls_header">
		<text>NIMBLE'S HANDBOOK</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_number">
		<text>Excerpt #</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_1">
		<text>Rank has eight different levels and can be increased through almost any in-game activity. Certain features may require reaching a high rank before they can be used.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_2">
		<text>Achievements can be unlocked through in-game accomplishments or by reaching statistical milestones. Every achievement is unlocked with an appropriate reward.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_3">
		<text>Basic, advanced and expert tools are required by most technicians in order to perform certain upgrades on weapons and outfits. Such items can often be found in stashes received as rewards for completing tasks.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_4">
		<text>Sleep deprivation is an optional feature where the passage of time and usage of consumables will gradually drain your character, eventually requiring you to rest. Failing to do so may have dire consequences.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_5">
		<text>Helicopter gunships can be seen patrolling many of the Zone's locations. When engaged in combat members of the helicopter's faction may often call on it for air support to help destroy attacking or defending forces.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_6">
		<text>Ironman mode gives a true sense of mortality. When your character is killed all saves for that specific playthrough are deleted and can never be restored. Pick your faction and starting location wisely.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_7">
		<text>Gunsmith and sewing kits are used to repair your weapons and outfits respectively when out in the field. Each allows up to three uses and are best used to repair items of greater value than the kits themselves.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_8">
		<text>Backpacks can be bought or found and then used to create a custom stash. Stashes created by your character are never de-spawned nor are they ever looted by other stalkers. They are permanent until all items are removed.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_9">
		<text>Sleeping bags are a great way to rest in the Zone if you are unable to find a decent bed to sleep in. They can be purchased from most major traders or potentially found in another stalker's stash.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_10">
		<text>Truck Cemetery is a large graveyard of irradiated agricultural, civilian and military vehicles. As a great place to hide a stash, an eagle-eyed stalker may find many valuables among the wreckage.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_11">
		<text>Artefact types are indicative of the anomalies they are found in. Want one that boosts your burn resistance? Search for a 'Burner' or 'Comet' anomaly and go hunting with your detector.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_12">
		<text>Completing tasks for factions will increase your goodwill with them. As it increases their traders will gradually offer you greater discounts on their goods and services.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_13">
		<text>Most tasks can be cancelled after you agree to complete them. You can do this by speaking with the stalker who gave you the task. Just remember that cancelling a task will decrease your reputation and goodwill.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_14">
		<text>Reputation represents how a stalker interacts with others in the Zone. It is gained and lost by helping or harming non-hostile stalkers respectively.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_15">
		<text>Remember to ask regular stalkers if they have any jobs available. Just because they aren't anybody important doesn't mean they won't be willing to pay you to do their dirty work.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_16">
		<text>Rostok's arena hosts two types of competitions: the traditional fights where stalkers battle each other for cash rewards, or challenges where they attempt to kill increasingly harder mutants.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_17">
		<text>Online exclusion radius can be set via the game options and defaults to 25. It creates a no-spawn zone around your character preventing mutants and other stalkers spawning unfairly and dangerously close.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_18">
		<text>Freedom completely occupies Yanov Station in Jupiter after a mysterious stalker assisted them several years ago. Some of their well-known members have since relocated to their new northern base.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_19">
		<text>The 'Completionist' achievement is received for unlocking all other available achievements. How many achievements are available to you depends on your faction and whether or not story mode is enabled.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_20">
		<text>It is much easier to avoid detection when travelling during the night or through heavy rain. However, you risk encountering fierce nocturnal mutants.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_21">
		<text>You won't be able to issue orders to companions if you leave them behind. Companions in Wait or Patrol modes will not travel with you when you move into a different level.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_22">
		<text>Vodka is a useful alternative to anti-radiation drugs if they are in short supply. It also weighs quite a lot and increases your hunger when used.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_23">
		<text>Not sure how to earn that achievement? Don't know what this feature does? The 'Guide' tab of your PDA has all essential articles unlocked right from the start.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
